{
    "id": "47_Health_224",
    "claim": "This food, originally from Turkey, could be banned because of its links with cardiovascular diseases.Before the stir generated by this news, from the European Commission press in Spanish have denied that it will be prohibited to sell.Kebab lovers have to worry, because soon they could stop eating it. The European Parliament's Health Committee rejected on Tuesday a proposal from the European Commission authorising the presence as phosphate additives in kebab meat, whether of lamb, veal or chicken, for its possible effects on human health. I mean, the European Union could make this kind of food illegal. Faced with the uproar generated by this news, from the Commission's Spanish-language Twitter account, they have denied that the sale will be banned. Neither the Commission nor any Member State is questioning the use of phosphate as an additive which is important for the food safety of preparations such as kebabs. I'm sorry. This objection was adopted with  votes in favour and  against in the parliamentary committee and the Brussels proposal will be blocked if it also receives the support of the European Parliament during the plenary session in mid-December. Food, originally from Turkey, could be banned due to its links with cardiovascular diseases, as explained by Metro UK. However, owners of premises where this type of food is sold are beginning to respond to the possibility of its being banned, especially in Germany, arguing that the meat they use needs these additives to remain juicy and full of flavor, both during transport and in their roasters. There have also been allegations of discrimination against kebab because some sausages containing phosphates would still be allowed. They are looking for ways to harm Turkish companies here, has assured the aforementioned medium Baris Donmez, owner of a kebab restaurant open at  hours in the Berlin district of Mitte. If the European Parliament gets away with it, this would be the death sentence for the entire kebab donor industry in the European Union, said Kenan Koyuncu, from the German Association of Producers of Doner Kebab, to the German daily Bild. Renate Sommer, a member of German Chancellor Angela Merkel's conservative party in the European Parliament, wrote on Facebook that the ban on the addition of phosphate would be the end of donor production and lead to the loss of thousands of jobs. European standards generally prohibit the presence of phosphates in meat preparations, but these additives are increasingly present due to the approval of derogations for certain products. The goal is to protect your taste and retain water. MEPs recall the existence of studies by  and  which demonstrate the relationship of phosphates in food with higher cardiovascular risks. The European Food Safety Agency (EFSA), on the other hand, excludes the possibility of attributing this risk to phosphate intake. This European agency, in any case, has ensured that it will re-evaluate the possible effects of phosphates on food as additives before next year's NUMBER*. I'm sorry.",
    "source": "www.abc.es",
    "date": "03/12/2017",
    "veracity": 0,
    "claims": [
        {
            "claim": "This food, originally from Turkey , could be banned because of links with cardiovascular diseases.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What country was the food originally from?",
                    "answer": "Turkey"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Where was the food originally from?",
                    "score": 0.8189,
                    "answers": "www.abc.es said on 03/12/2017 that This food , originally from Turkey , could be banned because of links with cardiovascular diseases|ROOT\tThis food , originally from Turkey|nsubjpass\toriginally|advmod\toriginally from Turkey|relcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the food banned from Turkey?",
                    "score": 0.8031,
                    "answers": "on 03/12/2017|prep\tThis|det\t,|punct\t,|punct\tbe|auxpass\tthat This food , originally from Turkey , could be banned because of links with cardiovascular diseases|ccomp"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Before the stir generated by this news, from the European Commission press in Spanish have denied that This food, originally from Turkey will be prohibited to sell.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who denied that food from Turkey will be prohibited to sell?",
                    "answer": "the European Commission press in Spanish"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What was the origin of the food originally from Turkey?",
                    "score": 0.7888,
                    "answers": "This food , originally from Turkey|nsubjpass"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the origin of Turkish food?",
                    "score": 0.7532,
                    "answers": "that Before the stir generated by this news , from the European Commission press in Spanish have denied that This food , originally from Turkey will be prohibited to sell|ccomp\tthat This food , originally from Turkey will be prohibited to sell|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did the European Commission press say about the claims?",
                    "score": 0.7079,
                    "answers": "the European Commission press in Spanish|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Kebab lovers have to worry, because soon Kebab lovers could stop eating This food, originally from Turkey .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who could stop eating Kebabs?",
                    "answer": "Kebab lovers"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Where was Kebab originally from?",
                    "score": 0.8218,
                    "answers": "eating This food , originally from Turkey|xcomp\tThis food , originally from Turkey|dobj\toriginally from Turkey|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many Kebab lovers have to worry about eating the food from Turkey?",
                    "score": 0.8003,
                    "answers": "to worry|xcomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the origin of Kebab food?",
                    "score": 0.7986,
                    "answers": "that Kebab lovers have to worry , because soon Kebab lovers could stop eating This food , originally from Turkey|ccomp\tbecause soon Kebab lovers could stop eating This food , originally from Turkey|advcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of Kebab lovers eating their food from Turkey?",
                    "score": 0.7754,
                    "answers": "www.abc.es|nsubj\tbecause|mark"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the origin of Kebab?",
                    "score": 0.7671,
                    "answers": "www.abc.es said on 03/12/2017 that Kebab lovers have to worry , because soon Kebab lovers could stop eating This food , originally from Turkey|ROOT"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The European Parliament's Health Committee it rejected on Tuesday owners of premises where this type of food is sold a proposal from the European Commission authorising the presence as phosphate additives in kebab meat, whether of lamb, veal or chicken , for possible effects on human health.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What was the European Commission's proposal to do with phosphate additives in kebab meat?",
                    "answer": "authorising the presence as phosphate additives in kebab meat, whether of lamb, veal or chicken"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Did the European Commission authorising the presence of phosphate additives in kebab meat?",
                    "score": 0.7577,
                    "answers": "www.abc.es said on 03/12/2017 that The European Parliament 's Health Committee it rejected on Tuesday owners of premises where this type of food is sold a proposal from the European Commission authorising the presence as phosphate additives in kebab meat , whether of lamb , veal or chicken , for possible effects on human health|ROOT\tfrom the European Commission|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is kebab meat?",
                    "score": 0.6481,
                    "answers": "kebab|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did the European Parliament's Health Committee say about the proposal from the European Commission?",
                    "score": 0.564,
                    "answers": "The European Parliament 's|poss\tThe European Parliament 's Health Committee|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "I mean, the European Union could make this kind of food illegal.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who could make this kind of food illegal?",
                    "answer": "the European Union"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What does the European Union do to make food illegal?",
                    "score": 0.91,
                    "answers": "on 03/12/2017|prep\tEuropean|compound\tthat I mean , the European Union could make this kind of food illegal|ccomp"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Faced with the uproar generated by it European Commission Spanish-language owners of premises where this type of food is sold that the sale will be banned.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who is responsible for the uproar generated by the European Commission?",
                    "answer": "Spanish-language owners of premises where this type of food is sold"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did the European Commission ban from selling food?",
                    "score": 0.7746,
                    "answers": "food|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What language is Spanish?",
                    "score": 0.7106,
                    "answers": "Spanish - language|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the uproar generated by the European Commission in regards to the sale of food?",
                    "score": 0.6932,
                    "answers": "Faced with the uproar generated by it European Commission Spanish - language owners of premises where this type of food is sold|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the name of the European Commission that banned the selling of food?",
                    "score": 0.6775,
                    "answers": "European Commission Spanish - language owners of premises where this type of food is sold|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Neither European Commission nor any Member State is questioning the use of phosphate as an additive which is the European Parliament for the food safety of preparations the European Parliament kebabs.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What additive does the European Parliament use for the food safety of preparations the European Parliament kebabs?",
                    "answer": "phosphate"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Why is the European Parliament questioning the use of phosphate as an additive?",
                    "score": 0.8454,
                    "answers": "www.abc.es said on 03/12/2017 that Neither European Commission nor any Member State is questioning the use of phosphate as an additive which is the European Parliament for the food safety of preparations the European Parliament kebabs|ROOT\tthat Neither European Commission nor any Member State is questioning the use of phosphate as an additive which is the European Parliament for the food safety of preparations the European Parliament kebabs|ccomp\tan additive|pobj\tfood|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the purpose of the European Parliament kebabs?",
                    "score": 0.7949,
                    "answers": "for the food safety of preparations the European Parliament kebabs|prep\tof preparations the European Parliament kebabs|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "This objection was adopted with  votes in favour and  against in The European Parliament's Health Committee and a proposal from the European Commission authorising the presence as phosphate additives in kebab meat, whether of lamb, veal or chicken will be blocked if a proposal from the European Commission authorising the presence as phosphate additives in kebab meat, whether of lamb, veal or chicken also receives the support of The European Parliament's during the plenary session in phosphates .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What happens if a proposal from the European Commission authorizing the presence as phosphate additives in kebab meat is blocked?",
                    "answer": "if a proposal from the European Commission authorising the presence as phosphate additives in kebab meat, whether of lamb, veal or chicken also receives the support of The European Parliament's"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Did the European Commission authorize the presence of phosphate additives in kebab meat?",
                    "score": 0.821,
                    "answers": "a proposal from the European Commission authorising the presence as phosphate additives in kebab meat , whether of lamb , veal or chicken|nsubjpass\ta proposal from the European Commission authorising the presence as phosphate additives in kebab meat , whether of lamb , veal or chicken|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "phosphates higher cardiovascular risks links with cardiovascular diseases, as explained by Metro phosphates .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What substance was linked to higher cardiovascular risks?",
                    "answer": "phosphates"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between phosphates and heart disease?",
                    "score": 0.7819,
                    "answers": "www.abc.es|nsubj\twww.abc.es said on 03/12/2017 that phosphates higher cardiovascular risks links with cardiovascular diseases , as explained by Metro phosphates|ROOT\ton 03/12/2017|prep\tthat|mark\tphosphates higher cardiovascular risks|nsubj\thigher|amod\thigher cardiovascular risks|appos\tthat phosphates higher cardiovascular risks links with cardiovascular diseases , as explained by Metro phosphates|ccomp\tcardiovascular diseases|pobj\t,|punct\tas|mark\tas explained by Metro phosphates|advcl\tby Metro phosphates|agent\tMetro phosphates|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "phosphates , this type of food higher cardiovascular risks this type of food are beginning to higher cardiovascular risks to the possibility of being banned, especially in Germany, arguing that the meat this type of food use needs these additives to remain juicy and full of flavor, both during transport and in roasters.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What type of food is beginning to higher cardiovascular risks?",
                    "answer": "phosphates"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Why is phosphates being banned in Germany?",
                    "score": 0.8385,
                    "answers": "being banned|pcomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the heart risks of using phosphates in food?",
                    "score": 0.7806,
                    "answers": "www.abc.es said on 03/12/2017 that phosphates , this type of food higher cardiovascular risks this type of food are beginning to higher cardiovascular risks to the possibility of being banned , especially in Germany , arguing that the meat this type of food use needs these additives to remain juicy and full of flavor , both during transport and in roasters|ROOT\tthat phosphates , this type of food higher cardiovascular risks this type of food are beginning to higher cardiovascular risks to the possibility of being banned , especially in Germany|ccomp\thigher cardiovascular risks to the possibility of being banned , especially in Germany|xcomp\tcardiovascular risks to the possibility of being banned|dobj\tto the possibility of being banned|prep\tthe possibility of being banned|pobj\tjuicy and full of flavor|acomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the purpose of phosphates in the meat used in roasters?",
                    "score": 0.7523,
                    "answers": "that the meat this type of food use needs these additives to remain juicy and full of flavor , both during transport and in roasters|ccomp\tto remain juicy and full of flavor , both during transport and in roasters|advcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the effects of phosphates on heart rate?",
                    "score": 0.746,
                    "answers": "these additives|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between phosphates and higher cardiovascular risks?",
                    "score": 0.7449,
                    "answers": "full of flavor|conj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "There have also been allegations of discrimination against kebab because some sausages containing phosphates would still be allowed.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What do some sausages contain that would still be allowed in kebabs?",
                    "answer": "phosphates"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many sausages contain phosphates?",
                    "score": 0.838,
                    "answers": "some|det\tbecause some sausages containing phosphates would still be allowed|advcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the allegations of discrimination against kebab?",
                    "score": 0.8324,
                    "answers": "allegations of discrimination against kebab|attr"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the discrimination against kebab?",
                    "score": 0.8057,
                    "answers": "www.abc.es said on 03/12/2017 that There have also been allegations of discrimination against kebab because some sausages containing phosphates would still be allowed|ROOT\ton 03/12/2017|prep\tthat|mark\tThere|expl\thave|aux\talso|advmod\tbecause|mark\tsome sausages containing phosphates|nsubjpass\twould|aux\tstill|advmod\tbe|auxpass"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is kebab?",
                    "score": 0.8006,
                    "answers": "discrimination against kebab|pobj\tagainst kebab|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is phosphates?",
                    "score": 0.7623,
                    "answers": "containing phosphates|acl\tphosphates|dobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "They are looking for ways to harm Turkish companies here, has assured the aforementioned medium Baris Donmez, owner of a kebab restaurant open at  hours in the Berlin district of Mitte.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What is Baris Donmez's business?",
                    "answer": "a kebab restaurant"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Who owns a kebab restaurant in Berlin?",
                    "score": 0.7658,
                    "answers": "the Berlin district of Mitte|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did Donmez say about Turkish companies in Mitte?",
                    "score": 0.6915,
                    "answers": "to harm Turkish companies here|relcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the names of the companies that are trying to harm Turkish companies?",
                    "score": 0.683,
                    "answers": "that They are looking for ways to harm Turkish companies here|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who owns Baris Donmez?",
                    "score": 0.663,
                    "answers": "the aforementioned medium Baris Donmez , owner of a kebab restaurant open at|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is kebab?",
                    "score": 0.6339,
                    "answers": "kebab|compound"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "If the European Parliament gets away with it, this would be the death sentence for the entire kebab donor industry in the European Union, said Kenan Koyuncu, from the German Association of Producers of Doner Kebab, to the German daily Bild.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who did www.abc.es say would be the death sentence for the entire kebab donor industry in the European Union?",
                    "answer": "the European Parliament"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What would happen if the European Parliament got away with the kebab donation industry?",
                    "score": 0.7992,
                    "answers": "www.abc.es said on 03/12/2017 that If the European Parliament gets away with it , this would be the death sentence for the entire kebab donor industry in the European Union|ccomp\tthat If the European Parliament gets away with it , this would be the death sentence for the entire kebab donor industry in the European Union|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the punishment for the kebab donor industry in the European Union?",
                    "score": 0.7383,
                    "answers": "the death sentence for the entire kebab donor industry in the European Union|attr"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Kenan Koyuncu's role in the kebab donor industry?",
                    "score": 0.7324,
                    "answers": "www.abc.es|nsubj\ton 03/12/2017|prep\tthat|mark\tIf|mark\tthe|det\taway|prt\tit|pobj\t,|punct\tthis|nsubj\twould|aux\tthe|det\tthe|det\tentire|amod\tkebab donor|compound\tthe|det\t,|punct\t,|punct\tthe|det\tof Producers of Doner Kebab|prep\tProducers of Doner Kebab|pobj\tof Doner Kebab|prep\t,|punct\tto the German daily Bild|prep\tthe|det"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is Kenan Koyuncu from the German Association of Producers of Doner Kebab?",
                    "score": 0.6939,
                    "answers": "from the German Association of Producers of Doner Kebab|prep\tDoner Kebab|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is Kenan Koyuncu?",
                    "score": 0.6412,
                    "answers": "Kenan Koyuncu , from the German Association of Producers of Doner Kebab ,|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Renate Sommer, a member of German Chancellor Angela Merkel's conservative party in the European Parliament, wrote on Facebook that the ban on the addition of phosphate would be the end of donor production and lead to the loss of thousands of jobs.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did Renate Sommer say that the ban on the addition of phosphate would be?",
                    "answer": "the end of donor production"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did Renate Sommer write on Facebook about the ban on the addition of phosphate?",
                    "score": 0.7842,
                    "answers": "German Chancellor|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the purpose of adding phosphate to the world?",
                    "score": 0.7374,
                    "answers": "the addition of phosphate|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is phosphate?",
                    "score": 0.727,
                    "answers": "phosphate|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between Renate Sommer and German Chancellor Angela Merkel?",
                    "score": 0.6417,
                    "answers": "Renate|compound\tRenate Sommer , a member of German Chancellor Angela Merkel 's conservative party in the European Parliament ,|nsubj\tAngela|compound\tGerman Chancellor Angela Merkel 's|poss"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Renate Sommer's political affiliation?",
                    "score": 0.6315,
                    "answers": "a member of German Chancellor Angela Merkel 's conservative party in the European Parliament|appos"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "European standards generally prohibit the presence of phosphates in meat preparations, but these additives are increasingly present due to the approval of derogations for certain products.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What additives are increasingly present in meat preparations?",
                    "answer": "phosphates"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What European standards prohibit the presence of phosphates in meat preparations?",
                    "score": 0.9032,
                    "answers": "European standards|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the ingredients for certain meat preparations?",
                    "score": 0.8334,
                    "answers": "these additives are increasingly present due to the approval of derogations for certain products|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of phosphates in meat?",
                    "score": 0.8289,
                    "answers": "the|det\tthe|det"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is phosphates?",
                    "score": 0.8274,
                    "answers": "of phosphates|prep\tphosphates|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the approval of for certain products?",
                    "score": 0.8189,
                    "answers": "the approval of derogations for certain products|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The goal is to protect your taste and retain water.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the goal of abc.es?",
                    "answer": "to protect your taste"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the purpose of hydrated water?",
                    "score": 0.7743,
                    "answers": "that The goal is to protect your taste and retain water|ccomp\twater|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the goal of ABC.es?",
                    "score": 0.5656,
                    "answers": "The goal|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "MEPs recall the existence of studies by  and  which demonstrate the relationship of phosphates in food with higher cardiovascular risks.",
            "question_answers": [],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship of phosphates in food with heart risks?",
                    "score": 0.7945,
                    "answers": "that MEPs recall the existence of studies by|ccomp"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The European Food Safety Agency (EFSA), on the other hand, excludes the possibility of attributing this risk to phosphate intake.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who excludes the possibility of attributing this risk to phosphate intake?",
                    "answer": "The European Food Safety Agency"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Why does EFSA exclude the possibility of attributing the risk to phosphate intake?",
                    "score": 0.8874,
                    "answers": "that The European Food Safety Agency ( EFSA ) , on the other hand , excludes the possibility of attributing this risk to phosphate intake|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does the European Food Safety Agency say about phosphate intake?",
                    "score": 0.8716,
                    "answers": "www.abc.es|nsubj\ton the other hand|prep\tattributing this risk to phosphate intake|pcomp\tto phosphate intake|prep\tphosphate intake|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the risk of phosphate intake?",
                    "score": 0.8222,
                    "answers": "of attributing this risk to phosphate intake|prep\tthis risk|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does EFSA stand for?",
                    "score": 0.7953,
                    "answers": "The European Food Safety Agency ( EFSA|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What doesEFSA stand for?",
                    "score": 0.7696,
                    "answers": "European|compound"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "This European agency, in any case, has ensured that it will re-evaluate the possible effects of phosphates on food as additives before next year's NUMBER*.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did www.abc.es say on 03/12/2017?",
                    "answer": "it will re-evaluate the possible effects of phosphates on food as additives"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did the European agency say about phosphates on food as additives?",
                    "score": 0.8386,
                    "answers": "in any case|prep\tphosphates|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between phosphates and food as additives?",
                    "score": 0.752,
                    "answers": "any case|pobj"
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}